The easiest place to start using window functions is with functions that just count.
要应用窗口函数 最容易的地方就是仅使用计数
They don't actually aggregate.
这些函数实际上并不运行聚合
Row number does just what it sounds like.
ROW_NUMBER() 顾名思义
It displays the number of a given rows within the window you define.
是指在你定义的窗口内给定行的行数值
It starts at one and numbers the rows
行的编号从 1 开始
according to the order by part of the window statement.
按照部分窗口声明的顺序进行排列
Row number does not require you to specify a variable within the parentheses.
ROW_NUMBER() 并不要求在括号内定义变量
Here, we're ordering by the ID field which increments by 1 every row.
这里 我们根据 ID 字段进行排序 每行增加 1
So the ID and row num fields always have the same value.
因此 ID 和 row_num 字段具有相同的值
But if we order by occurred at,
但是 如果我们以 occurred_at（发生时间）排序
the rows are ordered differently,
行号就会不同
and the row num column is therefore assigned differently.
而 row_num 列也因此将被赋予不同值
You can see that the row number no longer matches up with IDs.
你可以看到行号与 ID 不再匹配
Using the partitioned by clause,
使用 partitioned by 子句时
we can start the count over at 1 again in each partition.
我们又可以在每个分区重新从 1 开始计数
Let's partition by account ID see what this looks like.
我们对客户 ID 进行划分 看看结果如何
This now shows us the row number within
现在显示的是每个客户 ID 对应的行号
each account ID where row 1 is the first order that occurred.
其中第 1 行是产生的第一个订单
There's another function, rank,
还有另一个函数 RANK
that does something similar. Let's take a look.
能够实现类似目的 我们来看一看
While this might look the same,
尽管可能看起来相同
there is a subtle difference.
但存在细微差别
If two lines in a row have the same value for occurred at,
如果连续两行有相同的 occurred_at 值
they're given the same rank,
对它们使用 RANK 后
whereas row number gives them different numbers.
ROW_NUMBER() 赋予这两行不同的编号
You'll notice this more if we date trunc the occurred at field by month.
如果我们按月截取(date trunc) occurred_at 字段的值 你会更清楚地了解这一点
As you can see, entries with the same month are now given the same rank,
你可以看到 月份相同的记录现在被赋予相同的排序
and the rank column then skips some values to make up for it.
然而 排序行会跳过几个值进行弥补
There's a similar function,
存在另一个类似的函数
dense rank, which doesn't skip values after assigning several rows with the same rank.
即 DENSE RANK 该函数在赋予这些行相同的排序之后 并不会跳过值
So you have this rows skips from rank 2 to rank 4.
因此 这一行从排序 2 跳到了排序 4
With dense rank, it goes straight from 2 to 3.
而使用 DENSE RANK 该行将直接从 2 跳到 3